the later model cars like Falcons and
Holdens and and everything else like
that when they're running on the um
unleaded they don't turn the distributor
which gives you or or change the spark
they actually pull the cam and they turn
the valve timing back they them
called duning and that makes you run
Norm if you were on your normal timing
for normal fuels with a normal
octane okay
um then that's you would set your
distributor your if you haven't got
distributor with points in it and
everything else you set your points at
the right Gap or you sent your spark at
the right you know amount coil resistor
condensers everything else computers you
set it the right kind of alignment spark
and then you set your spark plugs to
suit so anyway what I'm talking about is
re reg decided he wanted to get a little
bit better out of his cars make it run
better everything else so he's thinking
that you going to buy these special
really good spark plugs with
three electrodes on the end all right
three
points okay so they cost just six
cylinder they cost him 80 something
bucks okay for six of them okay so we
put them in and the motor was still hot
I fit them put them in motor's still hot
fired her up he thought it was okay he
went home he he didn't realize it you
used more fuel
okay we didn't change anything else to
suit just put the spark plugs in better
supposed one splitting your spark so
next morning it was in um just normal
conditions next morning he goes out to
start his car she don't want to start
she just don't want to start took him
ages to get the damn thing started so he
got her started and then he drives her
into town and when he drives her into
town she's jerking and farting and
missing and coughing and spluttering a
fair bit when she went up to a higher
temperature she started run nice okay
but then she drops down a bit in
temperature and everything go runs
terrible so we come in he said they
absolutely
wful he said where's me old plugs I said
in the bend we'll pull them back out put
them back in single point put them back
in M Run's beautiful all conditions so
he's really updated um spark plugs and
everything else what he didn't realize
is nobody's actually built them to suit
this unlet crack they were built for the
higher octane you know different kinds
of fuels and everything else even if it
is the first of unlet it's still you
know higher octane the crap we got today
so the plugs didn't match went back to
the original ones and she runs
smoothies why I'm telling you all this
whoever gets this is because you got to
start thinking a little bit
differently right you just don't go by
what you told about what makes engines
run and what doesn't make engines run
and how you can start them and how you
can stop them and what starts them and
what stops them and you know we might
not be
correct okay so back to it now yeah you
want to hear about the Suzuki well
listen if I told you the 100% answer so
simple and what you did about the Suzuki
then I'd you know I'd be sort of a
little bit in D Straits you know myself
because I'm the guy who knows it and
tells it and then if everybody goes out
and does it to every car mean the
there's no more excitement there's no
more challenge the the you know
mechanics Engineers scientists and
everything else might like me so much
because everybody else might think you
know youve done well you got cars
running now
without but that's not what they want
you kill an
economy they say and it's their economy
but they've made you relied on it so you
understand but you break a whole lot of
pton rules for a start because they've
set up all these things with pton on the
to make that car run the way it isn't
somebody paid a fortune for that so we
don't want to rub the wrong people the
wrong way but way way way way way way
way back people had um DC
magnetos these aren't your normal common
Magneto today even going back a 100
years because the original DC Magneto
was taken by the Air Force and armies
and everything else when they found out
they were hooked on engines and the
engines didn't have the spark plugs and
didn't have the points and didn't have
the condensers
didn't have the leads didn't have
Distributors they used to hook this
flame in one lead see the DC Magneto
some concept
different the DC mag get out of it the
DC Magneto and everything else actually
only had one
wire okay there was no other connections
and that DC Magneto one connection wire
and so like that that used to run any
engine by just putting it anywhere on
the engine from a one cylinder up to 12
cylinders that engine would fire every
time in every cylinder by one yeah so
what is that frequency Joe what is the
the DC you want me to tell you
now okay so the AC Magneto and points
condensers and coils and your name it
and electronics and everything got to be
broken back to Flatline DC anyway what
do you think your spark jumping across
your SP plug is
doing okay it drops it back okay so
they'll tell you with a full spark plug
we've been into this how you check a FY
spark plug pull your lead back outside
make it jump outside it's not building
up and making it jump more spark onto
the spark plug itself not or break it
anywhere up the up the line anywhere
back to your distributor or coil and
everything else and what you're going to
do is you're going to um you're going to
find that you're faulty spark like now
we don't go by stupid people and I'm not
going to mention Souls sorry stupid
people's names but somebody went and got
a good working spark plug and collaps
the end and bang the end clean over so
that's negative electrode off the spark
plug straight onto your Center Point
that with a hammer to prove my point and
they said didn't work flipping your dead
shorting negative directly to that you
carbon is a different
thing too by the
way not running the guy down it's just
misunderstanding the same but if it was
in front of your car you could could be
call it running over I didn't say
that he did um so the thing is you can't
grab a spark plug and Bash the Flaming
negative straight over into the center
of electrode and think that you're going
to make this idea in the concept work
see carbon is a different sort of an an
acting Force okay so you build up carbon
in spark plugs you short them out
through that and everything Gose through
the center electrode through or short
out or something like that it's going
through some other thing okay changes a
little bit so your concepts are you know
bit different so if you got a fly spark
plug you got a Miss in the motor you
pull it back a tiny bit make the spark
jump on the outside and that motor purs
like a kitten she don't miss you know
put it on misses Pull It Away misses but
you don't know what it is could be burn
out valve could be head gasket could be
piston could be anything but eliminated
it down to spark plug as we've been
there before and so on so we know it's a
spark plug without pulling it out and
changing it how do you check it just
pull the spark back on the outside now
spark plug is fly shorten now bug it not
firing either carbon up bu something
okay so you just pull the spark on the
outside back a little bit and the motor
go smoth it out straight St away okay
plug away put it back to the original
concept y okay back the way man's been
made to make it okay so that motor was
running without the spark jumping on the
inside was jumping on the
outside okay we've got the Commodore
spark jumping on the outside but not to
the spark plug we were to Jumping to the
air
conditioning does the engine run no but
could the engine
run well if it can shut down it can flip
and run if you can stop it the opposite
equal is run it ah so a frequency but
see we're back around the circle
a frequency from what you seen on the
commod through the Airing unit which
wasn't even turned on everything El shut
down the engine okay the Suzuki you want
to find out about right what makes an
engine
run I stop for a minute because I'll
give you that to think about
hang what makes an engine run now you
listen to that
anyway so sorry yeah you're right
there's a whole lot of
fuel everything and so on all the way
down through the lines okay so it is a
combination of things so it's not just
one thing but you can come back to
frequency does it okay your first DC
magnetos were taken by the Air Force and
Army and everything else and they use
them to this day and they use them to
send frequencies around the world your
voices and things like that okay now I'm
not going with them or against them or
anything El go out and chase them you'll
find it if you want to go and Chase it
up okay um now they might have altered
that frequency a little bit to suit
their sounds what they're sending now so
don't think you're going to go and get
one off the air force throw it on your
car and it's going to run there's a
possibility with some cars are
might okay but there's a possibility
they might not be some cars okay you
want to look at something else as is
what you're going road setup okay don't
know whether you know about them where
you are in America and everything else
but r o rust oxidization destroyed
electrically hopefully I got those words
right because I don't know but what
they're doing is using the normal
frequencies in a car now they sell two
boxes one is for computers